<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microdata on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>/tags/microdata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microdata on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015-2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/microdata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring housing data with R and IPUMS USA</title>
      <link>/2018/07/01/exploring-housing-data-with-r-and-ipums-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/01/exploring-housing-data-with-r-and-ipums-usa/</guid>
      <description>In this post I want to share some observations on housing in the United States from 1980 to 2016, share some R code for data wrangling, and tri (no that’s not a typo, just a pun) out a visualization techniques.
Let’s get to it.
I’ve been carrying a running conversation with folks on Twitter regarding the U.S. housing market and its future. Much of that depends on the evolution of demographic forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of kernels and beeswarms: Comparing the distribution of house values to household income</title>
      <link>/2017/04/16/house-price-to-income-acs-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/16/house-price-to-income-acs-2015/</guid>
      <description>BACK IN JANUARY WE LOOKED AT HOUSING microdata from the American Community Survey Public Microdata that we collected from IPUMS. Let’s pick back up and look at these data some more. Glad you could join us.
Be sure to check out my earlier post for more discussion of the underlying data. Here we’ll pick up where we left off and make some more graphs using R.
Just a quick reminder (read the earlier post for all the details), we have a dataset that includes household level observations for the 20 largest metro areas in the United States for 2010 and 2015 (latest data available).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>