<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demographics on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>/tags/demographics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Demographics on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015-2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/demographics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. housing supply and demand</title>
      <link>/2018/10/07/u-s-housing-supply-and-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/07/u-s-housing-supply-and-demand/</guid>
      <description>In this post I want review some trends in U.S. housing supply and demand. Specifically I want to look at county level trends in population, housing supply (the total number of housing units) and house prices. We’ll uncover some interesting trends.
Per usual we will make our graphics with R. Preparing the data required several steps that I will outline in a follow up post. For now we’ll just proceed with the data I’ve put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State population growth and house prices</title>
      <link>/2017/12/20/state-population-growth-and-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/20/state-population-growth-and-house-prices/</guid>
      <description>EARLIER TODAY THE U.S. CENSUS BUREAU released new estimates of population for U.S. states from 2010 through 2017. Let’s see how population trends look compared to recent house price growth.
We’ll combine the Census estimates for state population with the Freddie Mac House Price Index.
The chart below plots population growth rates by state from July of 2010 to July of 2017 against house price appreciation rates over that same period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing supply, population, and house prices: Tableau Dashboard</title>
      <link>/2017/06/05/tableau-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/05/tableau-dash/</guid>
      <description>I MADE A LITTLE TABLEAU VISUALIZATION TO ANLAYZE TRENDS in population, housing supply and house prices.
If you like interactive dataviz, then the best thing might be to jump down below and explore. But I’ll frame the viz with a bit of discussion.
This post extends the analysis from last time looking at population, housing supply and house prices. Last time we restricted ourselves to national trends, but here we’ll dig into local trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Density squared</title>
      <link>/2016/08/26/more-on-pop-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/26/more-on-pop-distribution/</guid>
      <description>WE ARE GOING TO EXAMINE THE DISTRIBUTION OF US POPULATION and make an animated gif combining a map and a kernel density estimate of the distribution of county population densities. Density of densities, or density squared.
We are going to use the same US County Population Estimates 1790-2010 we used in my previous post.
We&amp;rsquo;ll end up with this:
How do we do it?
Code First, we&amp;rsquo;ll load the data and do some manipulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. county population: 1790-2010</title>
      <link>/2016/08/23/us-pop-map-1790-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/23/us-pop-map-1790-2010/</guid>
      <description>SOMETIMES YOU ACTUALLY LEARN SOMETHING from social media. Today on Twitter I happened across this Tweet via @kyle_e_walker:
Anybody want population estimates for every US county &amp;amp; metro back to 1790? Well, here are mine. Have fun!https://t.co/QqdA6226kN
&amp;mdash; Jonathan Schroeder (@j_p_schroeder) August 15, 2016 
Seems somebody posted estimates of the U.S. population by county (defined by 2010 county definitions) going back to 1790. This is a perfect dataset to practice my mapping with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population growth, housing supply, and house prices</title>
      <link>/2016/05/22/population-growth-housing-supply-and-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/22/population-growth-housing-supply-and-house-prices/</guid>
      <description>EARLIER THIS WEEK THE U.S. CENSUS BUREAU released data on population and housing units for counties across the U.S. in 2015. These data reveal important trends in population growth, and help shed light on recent house price trends.
Housing unit growth One key factor driving housing market dynamics is the expansion of housing supply (or lack thereof). The updated estimates from Census allow us to see which areas have added the most housing units and how that relates to population and house price trends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>