<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tableau on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>http://lenkiefer.com/tags/tableau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tableau on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015-2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lenkiefer.com/tags/tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Housing supply, population, and house prices: Tableau Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/06/05/tableau-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/06/05/tableau-dash/</guid>
      <description>R statistics dataviz remix flexdashboard</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz: Occupation Wages and Regional Cost of Living</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2016/04/14/data-viz-occupation-wages-and-regional-cost-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2016/04/14/data-viz-occupation-wages-and-regional-cost-of-living/</guid>
      <description>A new data viz TODAY THE BLS released dataon metro level wages, employment concentration and regional costs of living.
I put together a quick plot and sent out the following tweet:
This post provides a link to interactive versions of the same plot and a discussion.
The data The BLS data is quite interesting. It combines estimates of the average annual wages by occupation in metro areas with estimates of the relative price level in those areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent House Price Trends</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2016/02/28/house-price-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2016/02/28/house-price-trends/</guid>
      <description>{% include JB/setup
National house prices rise 6.2% Freddie Mac released its full year 2015 house price index and an interactive data visualization. The seasonally-adjusted national index increased 6.2 percent year-over-year and is now 29.6 percent above the post-recession low, and just 4.1 percent below the (nominal) pre-recession peak (see graph below).
While national house price growth has been strong, there is considerable variation across the country. Some states and metro areas are already well above their pre-recession (nominal) peak, while other still have lots of ground to make up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotated Data Viz 2</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2015/08/29/annotated-data-viz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2015/08/29/annotated-data-viz-2/</guid>
      <description>BELOW IS A VISUALIZATION of household size and composition and homeownership from the Census1going back to 1980. With this visualization, we can see how household size and tenure choice (own vs rent) has varied by age over time.
1Data from Ipums: IPUMS-USA, University of Minnesota, www.ipums.org.
See my data visualizations on Tableau Public</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotated Data Viz 1</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2015/08/23/annotated-data-viz-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2015/08/23/annotated-data-viz-1/</guid>
      <description>Homeownership and the Jobs Outlook BELOW IS A VISUALIZATION of job growth and homeownership by occcupation. This viz details expected job growth by occupation compared to homeownership rate by occupation. This viz was originally published on Freddiemac.com. This viz shows compares variation in homeownership rates by occupation with expected job growth for those occupations. The size of the bubbles correspond to the expected number of job openings for that occupation. Projected job openings come from the Bureau of Labor Statistics, while the homeownership rate comes from the American Community Survey, public use microdata.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
