<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slides on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>/tags/slides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slides on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015-2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/slides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Model Averaging Presentation Slides</title>
      <link>/2017/10/30/dynamic-model-averaging-presentation-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/30/dynamic-model-averaging-presentation-slides/</guid>
      <description>I PUT TOGETHER SOME SLIDES SUMMARIZING our recent work on dynamic model averaging.
See here and here for more blah blah blah.
See below for some slides.
Click here for a fullscreen version here.
Making the PresoLet me also share with you the R code I used to generate these slides. The code below is the Rmarkdown I used to generate the slides (saved as .txt). The slides were put together using the xaringan package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining PowerPoint and R&#39;s tweenr for smooth animations</title>
      <link>/2017/10/22/smooth-animations-r-pptx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/22/smooth-animations-r-pptx/</guid>
      <description>IN THIS POST I WANT SHARE A METHOD FOR MAKING SMOOTH POWERPOINT ANIMATIONS USING R.
Also see other posts in this series:
Crafting a PowerPoint Presentation with R LINKPURRRTY PowerPoint with R LINKPURRRtier PowerPoint with R LINKMotivationWhy would you want to do this? We’ve covered how to make an animated gif with R and that works pretty well. But there are a couple advantages with this approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purrrtier PowerPoint with R</title>
      <link>/2017/10/21/purrrtier-powerpoint-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/21/purrrtier-powerpoint-with-r/</guid>
      <description>WE ARE ON OUR WAY TOWARDS BUILDING a tidy PowerPoint workflow. In this post I want to build on my earlier posts (see here for an introduction and here for a more sophisticated approach) for building a PowerPoint presentation with R and try to make it even purrrtier.
I saw that somebody shared my posts on reddit and I thought I would take a look at the comments. Folks on the internet are known for kindness and offering helpful advice right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PURRRty PowerPoint with R</title>
      <link>/2017/09/27/use-purrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/27/use-purrr/</guid>
      <description>IN THIS POST I WANT TO GO THROUGH SOME EXAMPLES of using the purrr package for R.
Now there are already some great examples of how to use purrr. If you’re brand new to purrr (like I was not long ago) probably start with Jenny Bryan’s Purrr tutorial then see R for Data Science and also this presentation from rstudioconf (pdf). You can also check out this curated collection via Mara Averick (on Twitter: dataandme ) for a bunch of examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a PowerPoint Presentation with R</title>
      <link>/2017/09/23/crafting-a-powerpoint-presentation-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/23/crafting-a-powerpoint-presentation-with-r/</guid>
      <description>LOOK I DON’T HAVE ANYTHING BAD TO SAY about PowerPoint. Others have said it (see for example Tufte and Harvard Business Review). It’s a tool and a fact of life for many of us.
I am interested in making better PowerPoints. In this post we’ll use some R tools to generate a PowerPoint deck.
OfficeRThe package officer allows you to access and manipulate ‘Microsoft Word’ and ‘Microsoft PowerPoint’ documents from R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Ninja! Crafting a browser-based presentation and how I got (re)started with R</title>
      <link>/2017/02/04/hello-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/04/hello-ninja/</guid>
      <description>I GIVE A LOT OF TALKS. Some are formal presentations or keynotes to large groups, while many are in small group settings. Sometimes I get impromptu requests so I have to be ready pretty much at all times to give some sort of talk.
On this blog I’ve shared many different DATA VISUALIZATIONS which could be part of a talk. Many of the more complex visualizations-probably most of the animated gifs-wouldn’t work great in most presentation settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>