<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>http://lenkiefer.com/tags/office/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lenkiefer.com/tags/office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tour of U.S. metro area house price trends</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/11/08/tour-of-u-s-metro-area-house-price-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/11/08/tour-of-u-s-metro-area-house-price-trends/</guid>
      <description>HEY! HERE IS A VIDEO SHOWING HOUSE PRICE TRENDS around the United States.
Earlier this year we looked at how to get the data and plot it using R.
I made the video using the PowerPoint to .mp4 workflow I outlined here.
Below I’ll review how to build this file.
Get dataWe are going to use house price data from the publicly available Freddie Mac House Price Index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining PowerPoint and R&#39;s tweenr for smooth animations</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/22/smooth-animations-r-pptx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/22/smooth-animations-r-pptx/</guid>
      <description>IN THIS POST I WANT SHARE A METHOD FOR MAKING SMOOTH POWERPOINT ANIMATIONS USING R.
Also see other posts in this series:
Crafting a PowerPoint Presentation with R LINKPURRRTY PowerPoint with R LINKPURRRtier PowerPoint with R LINKMotivationWhy would you want to do this? We’ve covered how to make an animated gif with R and that works pretty well. But there are a couple advantages with this approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purrrtier PowerPoint with R</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/21/purrrtier-powerpoint-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/21/purrrtier-powerpoint-with-r/</guid>
      <description>WE ARE ON OUR WAY TOWARDS BUILDING a tidy PowerPoint workflow. In this post I want to build on my earlier posts (see here for an introduction and here for a more sophisticated approach) for building a PowerPoint presentation with R and try to make it even purrrtier.
I saw that somebody shared my posts on reddit and I thought I would take a look at the comments. Folks on the internet are known for kindness and offering helpful advice right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot as it was meant to be</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/03/ggplot-as-it-was-meant-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/03/ggplot-as-it-was-meant-to-be/</guid>
      <description>I’ve BEEN MESSING AROUND MORE WITH R and OFFICER and having too much fun for a Monday. I’m going to dive into some details later, but I’ll just leave a couple files here.
See the attached PowerPoint .pptx file for all the charts.
Here’s a gif version I started with:
Then after I created the PowerPoint I started messing around with the drawing tools and made increasingly ill-advised edits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PURRRty PowerPoint with R</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/27/use-purrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/27/use-purrr/</guid>
      <description>IN THIS POST I WANT TO GO THROUGH SOME EXAMPLES of using the purrr package for R.
Now there are already some great examples of how to use purrr. If you’re brand new to purrr (like I was not long ago) probably start with Jenny Bryan’s Purrr tutorial then see R for Data Science and also this presentation from rstudioconf (pdf). You can also check out this curated collection via Mara Averick (on Twitter: dataandme ) for a bunch of examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a PowerPoint Presentation with R</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/23/crafting-a-powerpoint-presentation-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/23/crafting-a-powerpoint-presentation-with-r/</guid>
      <description>LOOK I DON’T HAVE ANYTHING BAD TO SAY about PowerPoint. Others have said it (see for example Tufte and Harvard Business Review). It’s a tool and a fact of life for many of us.
I am interested in making better PowerPoints. In this post we’ll use some R tools to generate a PowerPoint deck.
OfficeRThe package officer allows you to access and manipulate ‘Microsoft Word’ and ‘Microsoft PowerPoint’ documents from R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
