<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data on Len Kiefer</title>
    <link>http://lenkiefer.com/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data on Len Kiefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lenkiefer.com/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Real House Price Trends</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2019/07/13/real-house-price-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2019/07/13/real-house-price-trends/</guid>
      <description>Let us take a look at house price trends in the United States and across states and metro areas.
Earlier this week I tweeted out a few charts on housing market trends.
In most of the middle part of the country over the past 44 years there has been little growth in real (inflation-adjusted) house prices.
In coastal states, a very different story. pic.twitter.com/PLbiNftha3
&amp;mdash; 📈 Len Kiefer 📊 (@lenkiefer) July 10, 2019  In this post we’ll analyze real house prices since 1975, and per usual use R to wrangle data and make plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent trends in U.S. housing markets: 2017Q3 update</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/11/05/recent-trends-in-u-s-housing-markets-2017q3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/11/05/recent-trends-in-u-s-housing-markets-2017q3-update/</guid>
      <description>LET US REVIEW HOUSING MARKET TRENDS in the United States through the first three quarters of 2017.
Economic backgroundThe overall economic environment remains favorable for housing. Interest rates are low, the labor market has been solid and income growth, while modest, has begun to tick up.
Low mortgage ratesFor most of 2017 mortgage rates have declined. Rates entered the year above 4 percent for the 30-year fixed rate mortgage, but after peaking in March, declined through September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage loan size distributions</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/05/mortgage-loan-size-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/10/05/mortgage-loan-size-distributions/</guid>
      <description>I AM WORKING ON ADDING some more analysis around mortgage origination trends (see here for a high level summary).
It’s on the way, but let me just leave a few graphs for you. These are updated versions of the same ones we made last year.
These infographics show the distribution of mortgage loan amounts by state/county and metro area.
For the beeswarm plots (see for example, Flowing Data) plots I have randomly sampled 2,000 loans from each state/metro area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage origination trends</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/29/mortgage-origination-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/29/mortgage-origination-trends/</guid>
      <description>IT IS SEPTEMBER AND THAT MEANS it is data release season. One of the most important September data releases for me is the annual HMDA data release.
These data provide the closest thing to a publicly-available comprehensive summary of U.S. mortgage market activity that we’ll get (for right now). The recently released data is for 2016 and provides a detailed view of mortgage market activity across the country. Let’s take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New home sales fall (maybe)</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/26/new-home-sales-fall-maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/26/new-home-sales-fall-maybe/</guid>
      <description>NEW HOME SALES FALL according to the latest new residential sales report from the U.S. Census Bureau and Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).
errr probably.
Remember, housing data is uncertain and there’s quite a large margin of error. Per the Census/HUD report sales fell 3.4 percent, but with a confidence interval of plus or minus 13 percent. Here’s a chart with the line showing the estimate and the shaded area the confidence interval around that estimate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing starts grinding higher or grinding to a halt?</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/19/housing-starts-grinding-higher-or-to-a-halt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/19/housing-starts-grinding-higher-or-to-a-halt/</guid>
      <description>ARE HOUSING STARTS GRINDING HIGHER, OR GRINDING TO A HALT?
Today the U.S. Census Bureau joint with the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development published updated estimates of housing starts through August of 2017. Per the report privately-owned housing starts in August were at a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 1.18 million, down 0.8 percent from July’s revised estimate and up 1.4 percent from a year ago. Neither the month-over-month or year-over-year changes were significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If housing inventory is so tight, why are so many homes vacant?</title>
      <link>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/17/housing-vacancy-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lenkiefer.com/2017/09/17/housing-vacancy-trends/</guid>
      <description>LET US REVIEW SOME INTERESTING TRENDS IN HOUSING VACANCIES for the United States.
Earlier this year we talked about how limited housing supply was helping to drive accelerating house prices across the country. In such an environment you would expect to see housing vacancies decline. Indeed, if you look at the rate of rental or homeowner vacancies you see a substantial reduction.
The chart below shows the homeowner and rental vacancy rates reported by the U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
